<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homepage on PRIME</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/</link><description>Recent content in Homepage on PRIME</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 19:29:15 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.primecommunities.online/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accounting</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/services/accounting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/services/accounting/</guid><description>&lt;p>Financial accounting (or financial accountancy) is the field of accounting concerned with the &lt;strong>summary, analysis and reporting&lt;/strong> of financial transactions related to a business.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Business Advisory</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/services/business-advisory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/services/business-advisory/</guid><description>Business Advisory is a specialized account service that offers expert guidance and strategic support to businesses.</description></item><item><title>Business Sales</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/services/business-sales/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:26 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/services/business-sales/</guid><description>&lt;p>Business Sales refers to the process of selling a company or its assets to interested buyers, often involving the transfer of ownership and control.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mergers</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/services/mergers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/services/mergers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Mergers involve the combination of two or more companies into a single entity, typically aimed at achieving synergies, expanding market presence, or enhancing competitive advantages.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Superannuation</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/services/superannuation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:54 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/services/superannuation/</guid><description>&lt;p>We provide expert guidance on setting up and structuring superannuation funds, ensuring compliance with regulatory requirements, and implementing tax-efficient strategies.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tax Preparation</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/services/tax-preperation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/services/tax-preperation/</guid><description>Our tax preparation accounting service offers a reliable and efficient solution for individuals and businesses seeking expert assistance in managing their tax obligations.</description></item><item><title>Agnes Kukulska-Hulme</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/agnes-kukulska/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/agnes-kukulska/</guid><description>Agnes worked in the fields of linguistics and language learning before expanding her expertise to encompass online education and learning technology. Her PhD was non-technical computer users’ attempts to understand computer security. Within her role as Professor at The Open University she leads the Learning Futures Research and Innovation Programme. Her research has a focus on informal learning with smartphones. She is currently leading several projects investigating mobile technology, teacher education, and English language use in low-income countries and among marginalised communities including migrants and refugees.</description></item><item><title>Andy Edmondson</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/andy-edmondson/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/andy-edmondson/</guid><description>Andy is a 1st year Edinburgh Centre for Robotics student researching the use of Hybrid Machine Learning Models to improve the strategic decision-making of autonomous robotic agents. Andy has an MSc in Artificial Intelligence from Heriot-Watt University. His main research interests are Reinforcement Learning and Robotics.</description></item><item><title>Aunam Quyoum</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/aunam-quyoum/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/aunam-quyoum/</guid><description>Dr Aunam Quyoum is a researcher at the University of Glasgow. Aunam holds a PhD in Education from the University of Sheffield funded by the ESRC. Her research experience and interests align to themes of anti-racism, social justice and participatory methodologies. She is co-lead on a work package for PRIME which will bring together a range of stakeholders across England and Scotland to exchange knowledge and co-design solutions to ethnicity related bias and digital discrimination in AI and digital services.</description></item><item><title>Deborah Menezes</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/deborah-menezes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/deborah-menezes/</guid><description>Dr. Deborah Menezes is an academic with vast international scholarship spanning Social Policy, Political Science, Urban Studies, and Human Geography. She has proven expertise in both the theory and practice of knowledge mobilisation, knowledge exchange, research design approaches and co-production of knowledge. Her research primarily focuses on urban and social policy, with emphasis on implications for housing outcomes, care provision and wellbeing across diverse marginalized communities. A critical scholarship rooted in intersectional, collaborative, value-based, and global paradigms best describes her pedagogical position.</description></item><item><title>Eunice Anteh</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/eunice-anteh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/eunice-anteh/</guid><description>Eunice is currently pursuing a Ph.D. in Urban Studies at Heriot-Watt University, Edinburgh, UK. Her research project examines refugee women&amp;rsquo;s experiences in accessing digital mental health services. Eunice earned her Master’s in health sciences from the University of Lethbridge, Canada and a Bachelor’s in health services administration from the University of Ghana. Eunice has an academic and professional experience in women and child health, refugee and migrant issues, social innovation, youth empowerment, entrepreneurship, program development, and creating and analysing health databases.</description></item><item><title>Farjana Islam</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/farjana-islam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/farjana-islam/</guid><description>Dr. Farjana Islam is an experienced researcher with an interest in exploring the dynamics of socio-spatial exclusions and inequalities to manoeuvre strategies for equity and inclusion. She has empirical experience of working with socio-economically disadvantaged and minoritised communities in the UK and in the countries of the Global South. She is a co-convenor of the BSA Race &amp;amp; Ethnicity Study Group and currently her works focus on exploring shapes and forms of health inequalities and housing challenges as perceived by the underserved and marginalised groups in the UK.</description></item><item><title>Gina Neto</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/gina-neto/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/gina-neto/</guid><description>My research explores the relationship between the lived experiences of individuals with a migration history and the engagement of public and other organisations with such individuals. Areas of focus include minoritised ethnic communities’ access to, experiences of and outcomes of engaging with key public services (including housing, health and social care services); participation in the labour market and creative industries; identity negotiation in multilingual physical and virtual environments, and approaches to tackling hate crime.</description></item><item><title>Irina Rets</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/irina-rets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/irina-rets/</guid><description>Dr Irina Rets is a Senior Research Fellow and a Lecturer in Online Teaching at the Institute of Educational Technology at the Open University (UK). Irina is also a Visiting Researcher in the Department of Management Science at Lancaster University. Her research seeks to understand how technology can be leveraged to improve social justice in the learning contexts, and more generally - in society. Irina is a Fellow of Higher Education Academy (FHEA).</description></item><item><title>Kefan Chen</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/kefan-chen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/kefan-chen/</guid><description>Kefan Chen is currently a Ph.D Student at Heriot-Watt University under the guidance of Prof. Lynne Baillie and Dr. Wei Pang. His research focuses on Explainable AI, AI fairness, and Human-Computer Interaction. Kefan earned his Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Electronic Information Science and Technology in 2018. In 2019, he achieved a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Artificial Intelligence from the University of Aberdeen, graduating with distinction. Following his academic accomplishments, Kefan gained valuable industry experience by working in a game development company and a software company&amp;rsquo;s research lab for two and a half years.</description></item><item><title>Laura Whyte</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/laura-whyte/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/laura-whyte/</guid><description>Laura completed a PhD in astrophysics at the University of Nottingham in 2004. After a brief stint in adult education, Laura retrained to teach secondary school in 2006. Several enjoyable years of teaching teenagers Maths, Physics, and Astronomy were followed by a move to Chicago to work at the Alder Planetarium as an educator and web-developer for the Zooniverse, the world’s largest and most popular online citizen science project. Laura was eventually promoted to run the Zooniverse team alongside the Adler’s Teen Programs and Hack Day portfolio.</description></item><item><title>Liz FitzGerald</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/liz-fitzgerald/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/liz-fitzgerald/</guid><description>Dr Liz FitzGerald is a Senior Lecturer in the Institute for Educational Technology at the Open University and a Senior Fellow of the Higher Education Academy. She is the chair for the OU’s Postgraduate Certificate in Academic Practice (PGCAP), module chair for the microcredential HZFM888 ‘Teacher Development: Using Scholarship to Improve Practice’ and was the founding Director of the LTI Scholarship Centre (LATIS) from 2018-2020. She provides expertise in distance learning and teaching and knowledge exchange and previously taught on the Masters (MA) in Online and Distance Education.</description></item><item><title>Lynne Baillie</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/lynne-baillie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/lynne-baillie/</guid><description>Prof. Lynne Baillie has a PhD and MSc in Computing. She is currently the Director of the Interactive and Trustworthy Technologies Research Group at Heriot-Watt University. She was a Senior Researcher at the Telecommunications Research Centre in Vienna (FTW) from December 2002 - December 2008. She has been successfully involved in the user centered design of home, mobile and rehabilitation technologies for over fifteen years. She has a strong track record over 15 years in research management and leadership at a senior level in two countries (Austria and UK).</description></item><item><title>Mark Wong</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/mark-wong/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/mark-wong/</guid><description>Dr. Mark Wong is an expert in digital society and policy, algorithmic harm, and inclusive data-driven innovation. His research examines harms and bias of data/AI on Minoritised Ethnic people. He has served in advisory roles for the Scottish Governemnt and Publich Health Scotland, contributing to addressing issues of systemic racism in data design and infrastructure in Scotland. He is also a Principal Investigator and Co-Investigator for several projects funded by the EPSRC, ESRC, and NERC, e.</description></item><item><title>Mehdi Rizvi</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/mehdi-rizvi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/mehdi-rizvi/</guid><description>Dr Mehdi Rizvi is a researcher working on the PRIME project, with expertise in Human Computer Interaction. Rizvi’s research focuses on the design of interdisciplinary tools and platforms for citizens and domain-experts. Such tools often follow the no-code/low-code paradigm, tangible interaction, or easy to use toolkits, making the interaction by end-users easier. Outcomes of his work have been published in various international research journals and conference proceedings, and also have been exhibited to general public in the form of interactive art exhibitions.</description></item><item><title>Mennan Guder</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/mennan-guder/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/mennan-guder/</guid><description>Mennan Guder is currently a research fellow working on the PRIME project, where he employs machine learning and agent-based modelling techniques to extract valuable insights from data. His role involves collaboration with other universities.
Mennan holds a BSc degree in Computer Engineering, an MSc degree in Data Mining, and a PhD degree in Deep Learning. Additionally, he has a minor in mathematics.
During his 17-year tenure at the National Scientific Council of Turkey, Mennan served as a system architect and applied researcher.</description></item><item><title>Nazmiye Ozkan</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/nazmiye-ozkan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/nazmiye-ozkan/</guid><description>Prof Nazmiye Ozkan has a chair in Sustainable Energy Transitions at Cranfield University. Building on her interdisciplinary training as an urban planner, her research focuses on developing socio-technical systems frameworks, models and tools to identify and manage risks, opportunities and challenges associated with digitisation and decarbonisation of energy and transport systems. Over the last twenty years, she has been principal or co-investigator on research projects worth over £16M funded via Research Councils UK, the European Commission as well as government agencies and industry.</description></item><item><title>Sacha Hasan</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/sasha-hasan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/sasha-hasan/</guid><description>Dr. Sacha Hasan has experience in investigating public participation and the institutional spaces of the engagement of marginalised social groups in public societal practices. She is particularly interested in intersectionality, identity and inclusive public spaces in both their physical and digital forms. She is passionate about promoting a fair and equitable public realm and a people-focused space design. In 2021, Dr. Hasan led a participatory research project commissioned by the Mental Health Foundation and funded by Glasgow City Council that investigates refugee and asylum seeker communities’ engagement in civic forums with focus on the relationship between social inclusion and mental health and wellbeing.</description></item><item><title>Sara Bailey</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/sara-bailey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/sara-bailey/</guid><description>Dr Sara Bailey holds a PhD in the Sociology of Human Rights from the University of Essex&amp;rsquo;s Human Rights Centre. She is currently a Research Associate at the Institute of Educational Technology at The Open University. Her present research interests are centred on the ways in which structures of class, &amp;lsquo;race&amp;rsquo;, age and gender faciliate or impede access to social rights in an era of rapid technological transformation. Before commencing her PhD, Sara worked at the intersection of human rights and international development for UN agencies and NGOs in the UK, the Middle East and East Africa.</description></item><item><title>Sebati Ghosh</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/sebati-ghosh/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/sebati-ghosh/</guid><description>Dr. Sebati Ghosh is working as a Research Associate in University of York, UK, with Prof. Siamak Shahandashti. She is a part of the PRIME project where her main focus area will be security and privacy. In particular she will be responsible with constructing Privacy Enhancing Technologies (PETs) for minority ethnic communities. From November, 2021 to April, 2023, Sebati has worked as a postdoctoral fellow in University of Bern, Switzerland. There she has worked on authenticated data structures with Prof.</description></item><item><title>Siamak Shahandashti</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/siamak-shahandashti/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/siamak-shahandashti/</guid><description>Dr. Siamak F. Shahandashti is a Senior Lecturer (Associate Professor) in Cyber Security &amp;amp; Privacy at the University of York, UK. His research interests include privacy-enhancing technologies (PETs), applied cryptography, device and application security, and human factors in cyber security and privacy. His research has directly contributed to increasing the security and privacy of security standards such as ISO/IEC 11770-4, security applications such as password managers, payment systems such as contactless payment and Bitcoin payment Protocol (BIP70), and everyday applications such as mobile browsers.</description></item><item><title>Wei Pang</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/wei-pang/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/wei-pang/</guid><description>Dr Wei Pang is an Associate Professor at the School of Mathematical and Computer Sciences, Heriot-Watt University, Edinburgh. Previously he was Senior Lecturer (2017-2019), Lecturer (2012-2017), and Research Fellow (2009-2012) at the University of Aberdeen. His research interests include bio-inspired computing, machine learning (e.g. deep learning, autoML), qualitative reasoning, and most recently, explainable and accountable AI. He has authored 130+ papers with an H-index of 20. His research has been funded by EPSRC, ESRC, NERC, Royal Society, Royal Society of Edinburgh, and Cancer Research UK.</description></item><item><title>Yingfang Yuan</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/yingfang-yuan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/yingfang-yuan/</guid><description>Yingfang Yuan works as a researcher on the PRIME project. He focuses on using machine learning techniques to uncover insights from data and support collaborative work with other universities. He also aims to propose novel methods for solving ethnic minority related issues. His academic interests lie in machine learning and deep learning, with a particular focus on graph neural networks and AutoML. Additionally, he is interested in blockchain technology, XAI, and evolutionary computation.</description></item><item><title>Zinat Aboli</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/zinat-aboli/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 14:04:11 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/team/zinat-aboli/</guid><description>Dr Zinat Aboli is a researcher at Cranfield University. Zinat holds a PhD in Sociology from the University of Mumbai. Her research experience and interests include themes related to gender, socio spatial segregation, social justice, and inclusion. Presently her work in the PRIME project involves engaging with a range of stakeholders across England and Scotland to understand ethnicity related bias and digital discrimination in AI and digital services. As an Assistant Professor she taught a variety of academic university courses on media education to undergraduate and graduate students in India.</description></item><item><title>Final report of Shelter's project on Black and Black-Mixed heritage people's access to social homes in England</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-dm-mr-shelterfinalreport/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-dm-mr-shelterfinalreport/</guid><description>Dr Deborah Menezes and Dr Mehdi Rizvi | July 2025
Shelter has published a new report called &amp;lsquo;My colour speaks before me&amp;rsquo;. This peer-led research shows how racism and discrimination affect Black and Black Mixed heritage people’s access to social homes in England. PRIME team members Dr Mehdi Rizvi and Dr Deborah Menezes were part of this effort as members of the stakeholder advisory group for this project.
See full report and further details here: https://england.</description></item><item><title>Appointment to the "Consumer Protection &amp; Accessibility” working group, Ofgem</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-mr-ofgem-appointment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-mr-ofgem-appointment/</guid><description>Dr Mehdi Rizvi | June 2025
Building up from this engagement with stakeholders during PRIME, Dr Mehdi Rizvi has been invited to join the &amp;ldquo;Consumer Protection &amp;amp; Accessibility” working group, in an advisory capacity, for the Consumer Consent Solution initiative by Ofgem. This initiative caters to the need to create a technical solution for consumers to grant and manage their consent for sharing their household energy data.
This particular working group will advise Ofgem on the issues of protecting consumers, accessibility, and usability, as well as barriers for the digitally disadvantaged.</description></item><item><title>Excellent Presentation Award at the 5th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence, Big Data and Algorithms</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-wp-caibdabestpaper/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-wp-caibdabestpaper/</guid><description>Prof Wei Pang | 15 June 2025
Prof Wei Pang won the excellent oral presentation award for PRIME work on “Quantifying Cross-sectoral Discrepancies and Geodemographic Information Analysis in the UK: A report from PRIME” in the 5th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence, Big Data and Algorithms (CAIBDA 2025) held on June 13-15, 2025 in Beijing, China. People involved in producing the work presented in the conference were Dr Yingfang Yuan, Kefan Chen, Andy Edmondson, Dr Mehdi Rizvi, Professor Lynne Baillie, and Professor Wei Pang.</description></item><item><title>PRIME demo at Heriot-Watt Health and Care Technologies Showcase</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-mr-hctshowcase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-mr-hctshowcase/</guid><description>Dr Mehdi Rizvi | 5 June 2025
Dr Mehdi Rizvi represented the PRIME project at a major showcase event hosted by Heriot-Watt University’s Global Research Institute in Health and Care Technologies. The event, held at the National Robotarium, at Heriot-Watt’s Edinburgh campus, highlighted research that aims to transform health and care globally through innovation and cross-sector collaboration.
Dr Rizvi presented a technical demo titled “Supporting Minoritised Ethnic Communities’ Equitable Access to Digital Health Services.</description></item><item><title>Videos</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 07:06:14 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/</guid><description>Check out the PRIME project’s educational videos which highlight key research findings about the experiences of ethnic minorities. The videos focused on:
Social media and online harms Online social housing services Online (health) general practice services The videos are available in the following languages: English, Cantonese Gujarati, Hindi, Mandarin, Punjabi, Somali, and Urdu.
Watch all Allcantoneseonline (health) general practice servicesenglishgujaratihindimandarinpunjabisomaliurduonline social housing servicessocial media and online harmsGujaratiCantonese, online (health) general practice services • 2/26/25PRIME - online (health) general practice services - CantoneseAccessing Online GP Services: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This educational video highlights key research findings about the</description></item><item><title>PRIME Policy Briefs</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/policy-briefs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 16:29:30 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/policy-briefs/</guid><description> Technical Policy Briefing</description></item><item><title>Links and Media</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/links-and-media/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 14:13:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/links-and-media/</guid><description>Video report on PRIME findings &amp;ldquo;Digitalising essential services risks widening inequalities for minoritised ethnic communities&amp;rdquo; Led by Professor Gina Netto of Heriot-Watt University, the interdisciplinary research team examined the impact of digitalisation on healthcare, housing, and energy services across the UK. Conducted in four locations – Bradford, Manchester, Glasgow and the London Borough of Tower Hamlets – the study highlights the particular issues that minoritised ethnic communities face when essential services move largely online.</description></item><item><title>Posters</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/posters/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 13:42:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/posters/</guid><description>Experiences of African Refugee Women in Accessing Digital Mental Health Services Eunice Anteh, Gina Netto and Sacha Hasan | Black History Month 2024, FJSS Female refugees have higher prevalence of anxiety and depression but refugee women of African descent, in particular, face further substantial challenges from racial discrimination, unique cultural contexts, and systemic barriers that exacerbate access and use of mental health services. To investigate the needs and experiences of refugee women of African descent in accessing and using digital mental health services and to recommend strategies in the design and delivery of social and digital tools or models to improve these services.</description></item><item><title>Graphics</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/graphics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 11:11:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/graphics/</guid><description></description></item><item><title>Open University Newsletter reports on the conclusion of the PRIME project</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-ef-ounews/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-ef-ounews/</guid><description>Dr Liz FitzGerald | April 2025
The Open University (OU) has played a pivotal role in the PRIME (Protecting Minority Ethnic Communities Online) project, a major three-year research initiative led by Heriot-Watt University, which is set to conclude at the end of March 2025. The project has uncovered how the rapid digitisation of essential services in the UK - particularly in healthcare, housing and energy - has exacerbated inequalities for minoritised ethnic communities, especially those already facing digital exclusion, language barriers, and systemic discrimination.</description></item><item><title>Community Partners</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/partners/community-partners/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 06:12:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/partners/community-partners/</guid><description>The PRIME project is guided by a Community-Based Participatory Research framework, underpinned by the principles of equity, empowerment, agency, inclusion and knowledge-production. As such, PRIME is working closely with a diversity of community-based organisations that work with minoritised ethnic populations throughout the UK. We have four key community organisation partners who have been involved in the PRIME project since its inception:
BEAP Community Partnership (BEAP): BEAP provides services directly and through its partner organisations through which it aims to tackle entrenched deprivation and disadvantage in the Bradford area, particularly among the Bangladeshi community, supporting deprived communities to formulate and put into practice their own agendas for positive social change.</description></item><item><title>Advisory Board</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/partners/advisory-board/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 23:20:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/partners/advisory-board/</guid><description>Our Advisory Group ensures that our work is at the leading edge of research, policy and action. It plays a critical role in ensuring research excellence and relevance, identifying emerging challenges and opportunities, and advising on ways in which the PRIME project can translate knowledge into action. Drawn from across sectors, our Advisory Board puts people with lived experience at the heart of the project and includes representatives of minoritised ethnic community organisations, high-level policy makers, regulators, and academics.</description></item><item><title>Desing Guidelines</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/design-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 19:07:57 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/design-guidelines/</guid><description>Design Guidelines for Enabling Equitable Digital Services The target audience for PRIME project’s design guidelines are the people designing, managing, or improving any public-facing digital services.
The design guidelines are grouped into 4 over-arching sections, with further guidelines within each section. Guidelines are accompanied with resources and examples guiding how to fulfil these design guidelines. This is envisioned as a working document in which more resources and examples will be added.</description></item><item><title>Code of Practice</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/code-of-practice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 18:54:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/code-of-practice/</guid><description>Code of Practice The Minoritised Ethnic People’s Code ofPractice for Equitable Digital Services (ME-CoP) contains principles and recommendations to guide the development of a digital service.
The ME-CoP offers a guide to anchor your decision making about the purpose of digital services, its design, delivery, and use of people’s data, including but not limited to, race and ethnicity information. Through seven principles, it recommend show the design of digital services can helps afeguard against some of the inequities Minoritised Ethnic people experience in access, outcomes, and their experiences of services.</description></item><item><title>Academic Publications</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/academic-publications/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 18:10:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/academic-publications/</guid><description>Published Papers An Integrated Agent-Based Modelling and Machine Learning Framework for Enhancing the Digital Service Access of Minority Ethnic Communities Mennan Guder and Nazmiye Balta-Ozkan This paper introduces an integrated modelling framework combining Agent-Based Modelling (ABM) and Machine Learning (ML) to enhance digital service access for Minority Ethnic (ME) communities, specifically drawing on the Protecting Minority Ethnic Communities Online (PRIME) project. The framework leverages ML models to derive unbiased decision-making rules, influencing ABM simulations that explore online service perceptions based on individual attributes and environmental factors.</description></item><item><title>Posters Presented at Health and Care Innovation Conference for Early Career Researchers</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-healthcareconf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-healthcareconf/</guid><description>Dr Mehdi Rizvi, Eunice Anteh and Vijaya B Jagadeesan | March 2025
PRIME team members Dr Mehdi Rizvi, Eunice Anteh and Vijaya B Jagadeesan participated in the Health and Care Innovation Conference for Early Career Researchers, at Heriot-Watt University, Edinburgh, on March 26, 2025. Dr Rizvi and Mr Jagadeesan presented their poster on the PRIME Technical Toolkit, focusing on prototypes develped under the PRIME project focusing on health and minority ethnic communities.</description></item><item><title>PRIME project publishes educational videos in 8 langauges</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-sb-videos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-sb-videos/</guid><description>Dr Sara Bailey | 05 March 2025
Our research revealed that many minority ethnic individuals struggle with the use of online health and social housing services, and face challenges keeping themselves safe online when using social media. Our research further demonstrated that some minority ethnic individuals, upon facing challenges, feel disempowered and are unaware of the actions they could take to tackle the challenges they face. In some cases, the research participants even reported withdrawing from or delaying accessing services.</description></item><item><title>Keynote speech at the Iranian National Informatics Conference</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-ss-keynote/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-ss-keynote/</guid><description>Dr Siamak Shahandashti | 2025
Dr Siamak Shahandashti, Co-I PRIME project, delivered a remote keynote speech on privacy-enhancing technologies (PETs) at the Iranian National Informatics Conference, a national-level event focused on cutting-edge developments in digital infrastructure and information security.
The audience of over 100 participants included industry professionals, researchers, postgraduate students, and members of the general public. Dr Shahandashti’s talk explored how PETs can empower individuals by safeguarding personal data in digital systems.</description></item><item><title>Invited panel speaker at SCVO’s The Gathering</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-mw-scvo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-mw-scvo/</guid><description>Dr Mark Wong | February 2025
Dr Mark Wong was invited to speak on a panel titled “Putting People and Values at the Heart of AI” at The Gathering, the annual flagship event hosted by the Scottish Council for Voluntary Organisations (SCVO). The panel focused on ethical, inclusive, and community-driven approaches to artificial intelligence and digital innovation.
Held in Scotland, this regional event attracted over 200 attendees, including professional practitioners, policymakers, and members of the public.</description></item><item><title>PRIME publishes Minoritised Ethnic People’s Code of Practice for Equitable Digital Services (MECoP)</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-mw-mecop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-mw-mecop/</guid><description>Dr Mark Wong and Dr Aunam Quyoum | 2025
The Minoritised Ethnic People&amp;rsquo;s Code of Practice for Equitable Digital Services (MECoP), developed by Dr Mark Wong, Dr Aunam Quyoum, and Ankita Mishra, has been published to enable developers, service providers and policymakers to address issues of equity in the design and delivery of digital services.
It has already been used to provide advice by the Equality and Human Rights Commission (EHRC) in relation to their work on digital inclusion for the Welsh Government.</description></item><item><title>Best Paper Presentation Award at 10th International Conference on Signal Processing 2024</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-bestpaper-icsp2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-bestpaper-icsp2024/</guid><description>Prof Wei Pang | 21 December 2024
Prof Wei Pang, one of the Co-I&amp;rsquo;s of the project has won the Best Paper Presentation Award for his presentation titled “Quantifying Discrepancies in Online User Experiences and Modelling Geodemographic Data with Graph Neural Networks: Some Results from the PRIME Project”. This was presented at the 10th International Conference on Signal Processing, Sanya, China, Dec 2024. The authors of this work are Yingfang Yuan, Kefan Chen, Andy Edmondson, Mehdi Rizvi, Lynne Baillie, and Wei Pang Prof Wei Pang, Heriot Watt University</description></item><item><title>PRIME Multi-disciplinary Presentations at REPHRAIN’s ‘All Hands Meeting’ in Edinburgh</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-prime-md-presentation-rephrain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:17:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-prime-md-presentation-rephrain/</guid><description>Dr Sara Bailey | 18 July 2024
Now that the hard work of data collection and data analysis is drawing to a close, the project team was delighted to have the opportunity to bring together researchers from both the social and computer sciences to provide a cross-disciplinary overview of our key findings to partners and stakeholders at the May 2024 ‘All Hands Meeting’ which was convened by REPHRAIN.
Of course, with 10 months remaining on the project, a good deal of work still remains to be done, especially for the team members involved in developing privacy-enhancing technologies and explainable AI that will help mitigate the online harms faced by minoritised ethnic (ME) communities when accessing online services, but this was a valuable opportunity to reflect on the progress made across the project so far.</description></item><item><title>Presenting PRIME at Celebrating Spaces event, University of York</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-sg-celebratingspaces/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-sg-celebratingspaces/</guid><description>Dr Sebati Ghosh | June 2024
PRIME researcher Dr Sebati Ghosh presented the PRIME project at Celebrating Spaces, a regional open day hosted by the University of York aimed at connecting early-career researchers with wider audiences, including industry, the public, and the third sector.
The event attracted over 100 attendees from a diverse mix of backgrounds, including undergraduate and postgraduate students, professionals, and members of the general public. The PRIME presentation introduced the project’s goals and activities, sparking lively discussions about how challenges faced by minoritised ethnic communities in accessing digital and public services often reflect broader systemic issues.</description></item><item><title>Presentation at REPHRAIN Showcase by PhD researcher Eunice Anteh</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-ea-rephrain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-ea-rephrain/</guid><description>Eunice Anteh | March 2024
PhD researcher Eunice Anteh presented at the REPHRAIN Showcase, sharing the aims, rationale, scope, and methods of her doctoral research on African refugee women’s experiences with digital mental health services. The presentation formed part of a national-level event attended by policymakers and professional practitioners.
Attendees engaged actively, asking questions and expressing strong interest in the topic. Several participants offered resources and constructive suggestions to support the research, and some requested to stay involved as the project progresses.</description></item><item><title>New IGNITE Network+ Flexible Funding won</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-mg-ignite/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-mg-ignite/</guid><description>Dr Mennan Guder | 2024
PRIME team members have won a new funding from the IGNITE Network+ Flexible Fund worth £20000. The project titled &amp;ldquo;Navigating EDI Complexity: Addressing Challenges in the Energy Research Sector&amp;rdquo; would be led by Dr Mennan Guder (Cranfield University), with co-leads Prof. Nazmiye Balta-Ozkan (Cranfield University) and Dr Pegah Mirzania (Cranfield University)
This project investigates the impact of workforce diversity in the UK energy sector on the development and user satisfaction of digital applications, particularly among minority ethnic communities.</description></item><item><title>Appointment to Shelter's Stakeholder Advisory Group for Racism and Housing: Access to Social Housing</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-mr-dm-shelter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-mr-dm-shelter/</guid><description>Dr Mehdi Rizvi and Dr Deborah Menezes | April 2024
Shelter has invited PRIME team members Dr Mehdi Rizvi and Dr Deborah Menezes to be a part of their Racism and Housing Research Advisory group. The project has a focus on people of colour facing systemic racism and discrimination when navigating the social housing system.</description></item><item><title>Invited Talk at Scottish Policy Research Exchange seminar series</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-gn-spre/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-gn-spre/</guid><description>Prof Gina Netto | 2024
Prof Gina Netto, Principal Investigator of the PRIME project, was invited to speak at an online seminar titled “Unpacking ‘impact’ in academic-policy engagement,” organised by the Scottish Policy Research Exchange (SPRE) for the Scottish Government. The event brought together national-level policymakers, business representatives, and other stakeholders to explore effective collaboration between researchers and government.
Prof Netto shared her extensive experience of working with the Scottish Government, including commissioned research projects, advisory group roles, expert testimony to parliamentary enquiries, and the organisation of a major conference at the Royal Society of Edinburgh.</description></item><item><title>Workshops on findings of housing research in England and Scotland</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-gn-housingworkshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-gn-housingworkshop/</guid><description>Prof Gina Netto | 2023
Prof Gina Netto, Principal Investigator of the PRIME project, organised a workshop in collaboration with the Manchester-based Caribbean African Health Network, a key community partner. The event brought together 50 participants—primarily professional practitioners from housing associations and community organisations—to engage with findings from research on access to social housing in England.
The national-level workshop created a platform for dialogue around housing inequalities affecting minority ethnic communities.</description></item><item><title>PRIME Participates in ‘End Digital Poverty Day’ 2023</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-sb-prime-participates-edpd-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-sb-prime-participates-edpd-2023/</guid><description>Dr Sara Bailey | September 2023
End Digital Poverty Day, a nationwide initiative dedicated to raising awareness about the pressing issue of digital poverty in the UK, takes place annually on 12 September. This year, the PRIME team participated in End Digital Poverty Day by publishing some of the project’s key findings in a blog post for the Digital Poverty Alliance. The post centres the experiences of minority ethnic communities of digital poverty, drawing on 100 in depth interviews.</description></item><item><title>PRIME Presents at the Digital Inclusion Policy and Research Conference 2023</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-sb-prime-presents-digital-inclusion/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-sb-prime-presents-digital-inclusion/</guid><description>Dr Sara Bailey | September 2023
In September 2023, PRIME project team members Dr Sara Bailey, Professor Agnes Kukulska-Hulme and Dr Elizabeth FitzGerald presented some of the PRIME project’s key findings at the University of Liverpool-hosted Digital Inclusion Policy and Research Conference (DIPRC 2023). The presentation took a deep dive into the experiences of older Asian and Asian British-identifying adults of using digital healthcare, housing and energy services. According to the Office for National Statistics (ONS), Asian and Asian-British individuals over the age of 55 are significantly less likely to use the internet than White individuals in the same age category.</description></item><item><title>Blog post published at Digital Poverty Alliance</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-sb-digitalpovertyalliance-blog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-sb-digitalpovertyalliance-blog/</guid><description>Sara Bailey, Sacha Hasan, Farjana Islam, Aunam Quyoum | September 2023
Based on our interviews with 100 minoritized ethnic individuals living in England and Scotland, the blog post discusses how digital poverty, limited digital literacy, and inadequate language support are hindering access to digitalized services for minoritized ethnic communities. It highlights the challenges faced by these communities, such as lack of access to technology, the internet, and digital skills. The post emphasizes the need for tailored support and solutions to bridge this digital divide and ensure equitable access to essential services for all members of society.</description></item><item><title>Invited talk at University of Almería Summer School</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-mw-almer%C3%ADa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-mw-almer%C3%ADa/</guid><description>Dr Mark Wong | 2023
Dr Mark Wong was invited to speak at the XXIV Summer School at the University of Almería, Spain, as part of the module “Online harm and hate crime.” His talk focused on the use of co-design methods to address harms and racism experienced by Minoritised Ethnic people in digital services in the UK.
The international audience of 30 participants included professional practitioners, policymakers, and postgraduate students.</description></item><item><title>PRIME Panel at the Scottish AI Summit</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-prime-panel-scotttish-summit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-prime-panel-scotttish-summit/</guid><description>Prof Gina Netto, Prof Lynne Baillie, Dr Aunam Quyoum | April 2023
PRIME PI Professor Gina Netto (Heriot Watt University) chaired a panel which combined inputs from research team members Dr. Aunam Quyoum (University of Glasgow), Professor Lynne Baillie (Heriot Watt University) and community organisation partners Colin Lee (Chief Executive, CEMVO Scotland) and Charles Kwaku-Odoi (Chief Officer, Caribbean &amp;amp; African Health Network (CAHN)) at the Scottish AI Summit. The Summit, held in Glasgow at the University of Strathclyde, brought together key notes and inputs from experts in Scotland’s AI community to facilitate conversations with diverse stakeholders.</description></item><item><title>Next Steps Prime Survey</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-aq-next-steps-prime-survey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-aq-next-steps-prime-survey/</guid><description>Dr Aunam Quyoum | 9 March, 2023
A survey has been designed, piloted and translated into several community languages and is ready for launch later in March 2023. The survey is expected to hear from 1000 people who identify as a minoritised ethnic individual living in England and Scotland. We are working closely with our community partners to administer the survey and ensure our sample is reflective of the diversity of minoritised ethnic communities living in the UK.</description></item><item><title>Prime Interviews Completed</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-aq-prime-interviews-completed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 19:26:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-aq-prime-interviews-completed/</guid><description>Dr Aunam Quyoum | 1 March 2023
The PRIME team has gained detailed insight into the various challenges minioritised ethnic citizens are facing when trying to access digital health, energy and housing services. The task to conduct 100 interviews with individuals across England and Scotland, was made possible by working in collaboration with our community organisation partners. In particular, our community partners supported us to recruit many minoritised ethnic individuals who do not currently use digital services effectively or who may have been reluctant to participate in an academic research project otherwise.</description></item><item><title>Presentation at REPHRAIN Showcase 2023</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-gn-rephrain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-gn-rephrain/</guid><description>PRIME team presentated the PRIME project to delegates from industry, academia, government bodies and regulators. The government and regulator delegates included representatives from the Department of Culture, Media and Sport, the Defence Science and Technology Laboratory, the National Crime Agency, Ofcom, the National Cyber Security Centre, and the Home Office. The presentation and the subsequent Q&amp;amp;A session sparked a debate regarding the conceptualisation of online harms.
Prof Gina Netto, PI PRIME, Heriot Watt University</description></item><item><title>Invited Talk at Algorithmic Dwelling Symposium - University of York</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-mw-algorithmicdwellingsymposium/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-mw-algorithmicdwellingsymposium/</guid><description>Dr Mark Wong | Janauary 2023
Dr Mark Wong was invited to be a speaker at the Algorithmic Dwelling Symposium at the University of York. He increased awareness and understanding of the PRIME project&amp;rsquo;s aims, particularly in addressing inequalities and harms experienced by Minoritised Ethnic people in digital services, in housing, health, and energy.</description></item><item><title>Invited Talk at Tower Hamlets GP Care Group CIC</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-no-gpcaregroup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-no-gpcaregroup/</guid><description>Prof Nazmiye Ozkan | November 2022
Prof Ozkan gave a presentation to Tower Hamlets GP Care Group CIC on 21/11/2022. There were over 10 general practice managers attending the meeting. In my talk, I emphasized what PRIME project was aiming to do, which included advancing understanding the challenges they have been experiencing through increased digitalisation of services. This sparked discussions about how the PRIME project outputs can contribute to addressing these challenges and informing policy making.</description></item><item><title>New blog post on limitations of data and AI and what this means for Minoritised Ethnic people</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-aq-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-aq-blog/</guid><description>Dr Aunam Quyoum
The PRIME project Research Associate, Dr Aunam Quyoum, has written a blog post discusses how data systems are embedded in existing patterns of social and racial inequality, and can therefore reproduce discriminatory outcomes. The blog post has been cited and shared with more than 150 policymakers and civil servants in talks that Dr. Quyoum and Dr. Mark Wong conducted in 2022. This includes: 1) the Ofcom internal academic seminar Quyoum and Wong presented at, attended by more than 140 civil servants and officials of UK government&amp;rsquo;s communications regulator, Ofcom, and; 2) the REPHRAIN policy salon session attended by the UK Government&amp;rsquo;s National Crime Agency, Ofcom, and National Police Chiefs Council.</description></item><item><title>New podcast about harms and bias in AI and data on Minoritised Ethnic people</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-mw-podcast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-mw-podcast/</guid><description>Dr Mark Wong | May 2022
Dr Mark Wong was interviewed for a podcast series, Spotlight, hosted by the University of Glasgow. I discussed the harms and bias in AI and data on Minoritised Ethnic people, with podcast host, Prof. Graeme Roy (Dean of External Engagement, College of Social Science, University of Glasgow). In the podcast, I also added new understanding to the importance of how we collect ethnicity data and information to inform public policy - and how the methods we use to collect and process information can themselves lead to biases in decision-making.</description></item><item><title>Talk at REPHRAIN Policy Salon</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-mw-rephrain-policy-salon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-mw-rephrain-policy-salon/</guid><description>Dr Mark Wong and Dr Aunam Quyoum
15 civil servants and representatives of government/public sector organisation attended a talk given by me (Mark Wong) and our project Research Associate, Aunam Quyoum, both at University of Glasgow, about the project. The talk was part of a series of REPHRAIN&amp;rsquo;s monthly hour-long “Policy Salons” held online, as part of a new initiative aimed at encouraging knowledge exchange and open discussions between policy makers, law enforcement agencies and REPHRAIN, the national centre of excellence on cybersecurity based at University of Bristol.</description></item><item><title>Invited Talk at Ofcom Internal Seminar Series</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-mw-aq-ofcom-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-mw-aq-ofcom-seminar/</guid><description>Dr Mark Wong and Dr Aunam Quyoum
140 Ofcom civil servants and policymakers attended a talk given by Dr. Mark Wong and Research Associate, Dr. Aunam Quyoum, both at University of Glasgow and part of the PRIME project. The talk was part of the Ofcom internal/academic seminar series. Their presentation introduced how our multi-institutional PRIME project examines online harms and bias of AI and data systems on Minoritised Ethnic people in digital health, housing, and energy services in the UK.</description></item><item><title>New EPSRC IAA funding for collaboration with SMARTLEARN STUDIO Ltd</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-yy-iaa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-yy-iaa/</guid><description>Dr Yingfang Yuan | April 2022
Dr Yingfang Yuan was awarded £6,893 through the EPSRC Impact Acceleration Account to support a short-term collaboration with SMARTLEARN STUDIO Ltd. The funding, provided by the Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council (EPSRC) in the United Kingdom, aimed to support knowledge exchange and accelerate the real-world application of research findings.
This project facilitated targeted engagement and innovation activities between academia and industry, contributing to the development and refinement of learning technologies through expert input from both sectors.</description></item><item><title>Contact us</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/contact/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/contact/</guid><description>Dr. Mehdi Rizvi: S.Rizvi@hw.ac.uk or Prof Gina Netto G.Netto@hw.ac.uk</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online (health) general practice services - Cantonese</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-cantonese/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-cantonese/</guid><description>Accessing Online GP Services: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This educational video highlights key research findings about the</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online (health) general practice services - English</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-english/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-english/</guid><description>Accessing Online GP Services: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This educational video highlights key research findings about the</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online (health) general practice services - Gujarati</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-gujarati/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-gujarati/</guid><description>Accessing Online GP Services: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This educational video highlights key research findings about the</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online (health) general practice services - Hindi</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-hindi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-hindi/</guid><description>Accessing Online GP Services: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This educational video highlights key research findings about the</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online (health) general practice services - Mandarin</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-mandarin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-mandarin/</guid><description>Accessing Online GP Services: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This educational video highlights key research findings about the</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online (health) general practice services - punjabi</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-punjabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-punjabi/</guid><description>Accessing Online GP Services: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This educational video highlights key research findings about the</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online (health) general practice services - Somali</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-somali/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-somali/</guid><description>Accessing Online GP Services: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This educational video highlights key research findings about the</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online (health) general practice services - Urdu</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-urdu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/health-urdu/</guid><description>Accessing Online GP Services: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This educational video highlights key research findings about the</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online social housing services – Cantonese</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-cantonese/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-cantonese/</guid><description>Accessing Social Housing Services Online: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This video shares key research findings about the experiences of ethnic</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online social housing services – English</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-english/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-english/</guid><description>Accessing Social Housing Services Online: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This video shares key research findings about the experiences of ethnic</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online social housing services – Gujarati</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-gujarati/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-gujarati/</guid><description>Accessing Social Housing Services Online: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This video shares key research findings about the experiences of ethnic</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online social housing services – Hindi</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-hindi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-hindi/</guid><description>Accessing Social Housing Services Online: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This video shares key research findings about the experiences of ethnic</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online social housing services – Mandarin</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-mandarin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-mandarin/</guid><description>Accessing Social Housing Services Online: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This video shares key research findings about the experiences of ethnic</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online social housing services – punjabi</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-punjabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-punjabi/</guid><description>Accessing Social Housing Services Online: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This video shares key research findings about the experiences of ethnic</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online social housing services – Somali</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-somali/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-somali/</guid><description>Accessing Social Housing Services Online: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This video shares key research findings about the experiences of ethnic</description></item><item><title>PRIME - online social housing services – Urdu</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-hurdu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/housing-hurdu/</guid><description>Accessing Social Housing Services Online: Guidance for Ethnic Minorities This video shares key research findings about the experiences of ethnic</description></item><item><title>PRIME – social media and online harms – Cantonese</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-cantonese/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-cantonese/</guid><description>Protect Yourself Online: Social Media Safety and Ethnic Minorities This video reveals key research findings about the negative experiences</description></item><item><title>PRIME – social media and online harms – English</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-english/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-english/</guid><description>Protect Yourself Online: Social Media Safety and Ethnic Minorities This video reveals key research findings about the negative experiences</description></item><item><title>PRIME – social media and online harms – Gujarati</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-gujarati/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-gujarati/</guid><description>Protect Yourself Online: Social Media Safety and Ethnic Minorities This video reveals key research findings about the negative experiences</description></item><item><title>PRIME – social media and online harms – Hindi</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-hindi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-hindi/</guid><description>Protect Yourself Online: Social Media Safety and Ethnic Minorities This video reveals key research findings about the negative experiences</description></item><item><title>PRIME – social media and online harms – Mandarin</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-mandarin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-mandarin/</guid><description>Protect Yourself Online: Social Media Safety and Ethnic Minorities This video reveals key research findings about the negative experiences</description></item><item><title>PRIME – social media and online harms – Punjabi</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-punjabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-punjabi/</guid><description>Protect Yourself Online: Social Media Safety and Ethnic Minorities This video reveals key research findings about the negative experiences</description></item><item><title>PRIME – social media and online harms – Somali</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-somali/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-somali/</guid><description>Protect Yourself Online: Social Media Safety and Ethnic Minorities This video reveals key research findings about the negative experiences</description></item><item><title>PRIME – social media and online harms – Urdu</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-urdu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/outputs/videos/social-urdu/</guid><description>Protect Yourself Online: Social Media Safety and Ethnic Minorities This video reveals key research findings about the negative experiences</description></item></channel></rss>