<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Team on PRIME</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/</link><description>Recent content in Team on PRIME</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 19:29:15 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.primecommunities.online/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Final report of Shelter's project on Black people's access to social homes in England</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-dm-mr-shelterfinalreport/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-dm-mr-shelterfinalreport/</guid><description>Dr Deborah Menezes and Dr Mehdi Rizvi | July 2025
Shelter has published a new report called &amp;lsquo;My colour speaks before me&amp;rsquo;. This peer-led research shows how racism and discrimination affect Black and Black Mixed heritage people’s access to social homes in England. PRIME team members Dr Mehdi Rizvi and Dr Deborah Menezes were part of this effort as members of the stakeholder advisory group for this project.
See full report and further details here: https://england.</description></item><item><title>Appointment to the "Consumer Protection &amp; Accessibility” working group, Ofgem</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-mr-ofgem-appointment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-mr-ofgem-appointment/</guid><description>Dr Mehdi Rizvi | June 2025
Building up from this engagement with stakeholders during PRIME, Dr Mehdi Rizvi has been invited to join the &amp;ldquo;Consumer Protection &amp;amp; Accessibility” working group, in an advisory capacity, for the Consumer Consent Solution initiative by Ofgem. This initiative caters to the need to create a technical solution for consumers to grant and manage their consent for sharing their household energy data.
This particular working group will advise Ofgem on the issues of protecting consumers, accessibility, and usability, as well as barriers for the digitally disadvantaged.</description></item><item><title>Excellent Presentation Award at the 5th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence, Big Data and Algorithms</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-wp-caibdabestpaper/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-wp-caibdabestpaper/</guid><description>Prof Wei Pang | 15 June 2025
Prof Wei Pang won the excellent oral presentation award for our PRIME work on “Quantifying Cross-sectoral Discrepancies and Geodemographic Information Analysis in the UK: A report from PRIME” in the 5th International Conference on Artificial Intelligence, Big Data and Algorithms (CAIBDA 2025) held on june 13-15, 2025 in Beijing, China. People involved in the work presented in the conference were Dr Yingfang Yuan, Kefan Chen, Andy Edmondson, Dr Mehdi Rizvi, Professor Lynne Baillie, and Professor Wei Pang.</description></item><item><title>PRIME demo at Heriot-Watt Health and Care Technologies Showcase</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-mr-hctshowcase/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-mr-hctshowcase/</guid><description>Dr Mehdi Rizvi | 5 June 2025
Dr Mehdi Rizvi represented the PRIME project at a major showcase event hosted by Heriot-Watt University’s Global Research Institute in Health and Care Technologies. The event, held at the National Robotarium, at Heriot-Watt’s Edinburgh campus, highlighted research that aims to transform health and care globally through innovation and cross-sector collaboration.
Dr Rizvi presented a technical demo titled “Supporting Minoritised Ethnic Communities’ Equitable Access to Digital Health Services.</description></item><item><title>PRIME project publishes educational videos in 8 langauges</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-sb-videos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-sb-videos/</guid><description>Dr Sara Bailey | 05 March 2025
Our research revealed that many minority ethnic individuals struggle with the use of online health and social housing services, and face challenges keeping themselves safe online when using social media. Our research further demonstrated that some minority ethnic individuals, upon facing challenges, feel disempowered and are unaware of the actions they could take to tackle the challenges they face. In some cases, the research participants even reported withdrawing from or delaying accessing services.</description></item><item><title>Keynote speech at the Iranian National Informatics Conference</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-ss-keynote/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-ss-keynote/</guid><description>Dr Siamak Shahandashti | 2025
Dr Siamak Shahandashti, Co-I PRIME project, delivered a remote keynote speech on privacy-enhancing technologies (PETs) at the Iranian National Informatics Conference, a national-level event focused on cutting-edge developments in digital infrastructure and information security.
The audience of over 100 participants included industry professionals, researchers, postgraduate students, and members of the general public. Dr Shahandashti’s talk explored how PETs can empower individuals by safeguarding personal data in digital systems.</description></item><item><title>Invited panel speaker at SCVO’s The Gathering</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-mw-scvo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-mw-scvo/</guid><description>Dr Mark Wong | February 2025
Dr Mark Wong was invited to speak on a panel titled “Putting People and Values at the Heart of AI” at The Gathering, the annual flagship event hosted by the Scottish Council for Voluntary Organisations (SCVO). The panel focused on ethical, inclusive, and community-driven approaches to artificial intelligence and digital innovation.
Held in Scotland, this regional event attracted over 200 attendees, including professional practitioners, policymakers, and members of the public.</description></item><item><title>Best Paper Presentation Award at 10th International Conference on Signal Processing 2024</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-bestpaper-icsp2024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-bestpaper-icsp2024/</guid><description>Prof Wei Pang | 21 December 2024
Prof Wei Pang, one of the Co-I&amp;rsquo;s of the project has won the Best Paper Presentation Award for his presentation titled “Quantifying Discrepancies in Online User Experiences and Modelling Geodemographic Data with Graph Neural Networks: Some Results from the PRIME Project”. This was presented at the 10th International Conference on Signal Processing, Sanya, China, Dec 2024. The authors of this work are Yingfang Yuan, Kefan Chen, Andy Edmondson, Mehdi Rizvi, Lynne Baillie, and Wei Pang</description></item><item><title>PRIME Multi-disciplinary Presentations at REPHRAIN’s ‘All Hands Meeting’ in Edinburgh</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-prime-md-presentation-rephrain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 19:17:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-prime-md-presentation-rephrain/</guid><description>Dr Sara Bailey | 18 July 2024
Now that the hard work of data collection and data analysis is drawing to a close, the project team was delighted to have the opportunity to bring together researchers from both the social and computer sciences to provide a cross-disciplinary overview of our key findings to partners and stakeholders at the May 2024 ‘All Hands Meeting’ which was convened by REPHRAIN.
Of course, with 10 months remaining on the project, a good deal of work still remains to be done, especially for the team members involved in developing privacy-enhancing technologies and explainable AI that will help mitigate the online harms faced by minoritised ethnic (ME) communities when accessing online services, but this was a valuable opportunity to reflect on the progress made across the project so far.</description></item><item><title>Presenting PRIME at Celebrating Spaces event, University of York</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-sg-celebratingspaces/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-sg-celebratingspaces/</guid><description>Dr Sebati Ghosh | June 2024
PRIME researcher Dr Sebati Ghosh presented the PRIME project at Celebrating Spaces, a regional open day hosted by the University of York aimed at connecting early-career researchers with wider audiences, including industry, the public, and the third sector.
The event attracted over 100 attendees from a diverse mix of backgrounds, including undergraduate and postgraduate students, professionals, and members of the general public. The PRIME presentation introduced the project’s goals and activities, sparking lively discussions about how challenges faced by minoritised ethnic communities in accessing digital and public services often reflect broader systemic issues.</description></item><item><title>Presentation at REPHRAIN Showcase by PhD researcher Eunice Anteh</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-ea-rephrain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2025-ea-rephrain/</guid><description>Eunice Anteh | March 2024
PhD researcher Eunice Anteh presented at the REPHRAIN Showcase, sharing the aims, rationale, scope, and methods of her doctoral research on African refugee women’s experiences with digital mental health services. The presentation formed part of a national-level event attended by policymakers and professional practitioners.
Attendees engaged actively, asking questions and expressing strong interest in the topic. Several participants offered resources and constructive suggestions to support the research, and some requested to stay involved as the project progresses.</description></item><item><title>Appointment to Shelter's Stakeholder Advisory Group for Racism and Housing: Access to Social Housing</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-mr-dm-shelter/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-mr-dm-shelter/</guid><description>Dr Mehdi Rizvi and Dr Deborah Menezes | April 2024
Shelter has invited PRIME team members Dr Mehdi Rizvi and Dr Deborah Menezes to be a part of their Racism and Housing Research Advisory group. The project has a focus on people of colour facing systemic racism and discrimination when navigating the social housing system.</description></item><item><title>Invited Talk at Scottish Policy Research Exchange seminar series</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-gn-spre/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2024-gn-spre/</guid><description>Prof Gina Netto | 2024
Prof Gina Netto, Principal Investigator of the PRIME project, was invited to speak at an online seminar titled “Unpacking ‘impact’ in academic-policy engagement,” organised by the Scottish Policy Research Exchange (SPRE) for the Scottish Government. The event brought together national-level policymakers, business representatives, and other stakeholders to explore effective collaboration between researchers and government.
Prof Netto shared her extensive experience of working with the Scottish Government, including commissioned research projects, advisory group roles, expert testimony to parliamentary enquiries, and the organisation of a major conference at the Royal Society of Edinburgh.</description></item><item><title>Workshops on findings of housing research in England and Scotland</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-gn-housingworkshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-gn-housingworkshop/</guid><description>Prof Gina Netto | 2023
Prof Gina Netto, Principal Investigator of the PRIME project, organised a workshop in collaboration with the Manchester-based Caribbean African Health Network, a key community partner. The event brought together 50 participants—primarily professional practitioners from housing associations and community organisations—to engage with findings from research on access to social housing in England.
The national-level workshop created a platform for dialogue around housing inequalities affecting minority ethnic communities.</description></item><item><title>PRIME Participates in ‘End Digital Poverty Day’ 2023</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-prime-participates-edpd-2023/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-prime-participates-edpd-2023/</guid><description>Dr Sara Bailey | September 2023
End Digital Poverty Day, a nationwide initiative dedicated to raising awareness about the pressing issue of digital poverty in the UK, takes place annually on 12 September. This year, the PRIME team participated in End Digital Poverty Day by publishing some of the project’s key findings in a blog post for the Digital Poverty Alliance. The post centres the experiences of minority ethnic communities of digital poverty, drawing on 100 in depth interviews.</description></item><item><title>PRIME Presents at the Digital Inclusion Policy and Research Conference 2023</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-prime-presents-digital-inclusion/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-prime-presents-digital-inclusion/</guid><description>Dr Sara Bailey | September 2023
In September 2023, PRIME project team members Dr Sara Bailey, Professor Agnes Kukulska-Hulme and Dr Elizabeth FitzGerald presented some of the PRIME project’s key findings at the University of Liverpool-hosted Digital Inclusion Policy and Research Conference (DIPRC 2023). The presentation took a deep dive into the experiences of older Asian and Asian British-identifying adults of using digital healthcare, housing and energy services. According to the Office for National Statistics (ONS), Asian and Asian-British individuals over the age of 55 are significantly less likely to use the internet than White individuals in the same age category.</description></item><item><title>Blog post published at Digital Poverty Alliance</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-ak-digitalpovertyalliance-blog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-ak-digitalpovertyalliance-blog/</guid><description>Sara Bailey, Sacha Hasan, Farjana Islam, Aunam Quyoum | September 2023
Based on our interviews with 100 minoritized ethnic individuals living in England and Scotland, the blog post discusses how digital poverty, limited digital literacy, and inadequate language support are hindering access to digitalized services for minoritized ethnic communities. It highlights the challenges faced by these communities, such as lack of access to technology, the internet, and digital skills. The post emphasizes the need for tailored support and solutions to bridge this digital divide and ensure equitable access to essential services for all members of society.</description></item><item><title>Invited talk at University of Almería Summer School</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-mw-almer%C3%ADa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-mw-almer%C3%ADa/</guid><description>Dr Mark Wong | 2023
Dr Mark Wong was invited to speak at the XXIV Summer School at the University of Almería, Spain, as part of the module “Online harm and hate crime.” His talk focused on the use of co-design methods to address harms and racism experienced by Minoritised Ethnic people in digital services in the UK.
The international audience of 30 participants included professional practitioners, policymakers, and postgraduate students.</description></item><item><title>PRIME Panel at the Scottish AI Summit</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-prime-panel-scotttish-summit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-prime-panel-scotttish-summit/</guid><description>Prof Gina Netto, Prof Lynne Baillie, Dr Aunam Quyoum | April 2023
PRIME PI Professor Gina Netto (Heriot Watt University) chaired a panel which combined inputs from research team members Dr. Aunam Quyoum (University of Glasgow), Professor Lynne Baillie (Heriot Watt University) and community organisation partners Colin Lee (Chief Executive, CEMVO Scotland) and Charles Kwaku-Odoi (Chief Officer, Caribbean &amp;amp; African Health Network (CAHN)) at the Scottish AI Summit. The Summit, held in Glasgow at the University of Strathclyde, brought together key notes and inputs from experts in Scotland’s AI community to facilitate conversations with diverse stakeholders.</description></item><item><title>Next Steps Prime Survey</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-next-steps-prime-survey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-next-steps-prime-survey/</guid><description>Dr Aunam Quyoum | 9 March, 2023
A survey has been designed, piloted and translated into several community languages and is ready for launch later in March 2023. The survey is expected to hear from 1000 people who identify as a minoritised ethnic individual living in England and Scotland. We are working closely with our community partners to administer the survey and ensure our sample is reflective of the diversity of minoritised ethnic communities living in the UK.</description></item><item><title>Prime Interviews Completed</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-prime-interviews-completed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 19:26:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-prime-interviews-completed/</guid><description>Dr Aunam Quyoum | 1 March 2023
The PRIME team has gained detailed insight into the various challenges minioritised ethnic citizens are facing when trying to access digital health, energy and housing services. The task to conduct 100 interviews with individuals across England and Scotland, was made possible by working in collaboration with our community organisation partners. In particular, our community partners supported us to recruit many minoritised ethnic individuals who do not currently use digital services effectively or who may have been reluctant to participate in an academic research project otherwise.</description></item><item><title>Presentation at REPHRAIN Showcase 2023</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-gn-rephrain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-gn-rephrain/</guid><description>PRIME team presentated the PRIME project to delegates from industry, academia, government bodies and regulators. The government and regulator delegates included representatives from the Department of Culture, Media and Sport, the Defence Science and Technology Laboratory, the National Crime Agency, Ofcom, the National Cyber Security Centre, and the Home Office. The presentation and the subsequent Q&amp;amp;A session sparked a debate regarding the conceptualisation of online harms.</description></item><item><title>Invited Talk at Algorithmic Dwelling Symposium - University of York</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-mw-algorithmicdwellingsymposium/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-mw-algorithmicdwellingsymposium/</guid><description>Dr Mark Wong | Janauary 2023
Dr Mark Wong was invited to be a speaker at the Algorithmic Dwelling Symposium at the University of York. He increased awareness and understanding of the PRIME project&amp;rsquo;s aims, particularly in addressing inequalities and harms experienced by Minoritised Ethnic people in digital services, in housing, health, and energy.</description></item><item><title>Invited Talk at Tower Hamlets GP Care Group CIC</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-no-gpcaregroup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-no-gpcaregroup/</guid><description>Prof Nazmiye Ozkan | November 2022
Prof Ozkan gave a presentation to Tower Hamlets GP Care Group CIC on 21/11/2022. There were over 10 general practice managers attending the meeting. In my talk, I emphasized what PRIME project was aiming to do, which included advancing understanding the challenges they have been experiencing through increased digitalisation of services. This sparked discussions about how the PRIME project outputs can contribute to addressing these challenges and informing policy making.</description></item><item><title>New blog post on limitations of data and AI and what this means for Minoritised Ethnic people</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-aq-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2023-aq-blog/</guid><description>Dr Aunam Quyoum
The PRIME project Research Associate, Dr Aunam Quyoum, has written a blog post discusses how data systems are embedded in existing patterns of social and racial inequality, and can therefore reproduce discriminatory outcomes. The blog post has been cited and shared with more than 150 policymakers and civil servants in talks that Dr. Quyoum and Dr. Mark Wong conducted in 2022. This includes: 1) the Ofcom internal academic seminar Quyoum and Wong presented at, attended by more than 140 civil servants and officials of UK government&amp;rsquo;s communications regulator, Ofcom, and; 2) the REPHRAIN policy salon session attended by the UK Government&amp;rsquo;s National Crime Agency, Ofcom, and National Police Chiefs Council.</description></item><item><title>New podcast about harms and bias in AI and data on Minoritised Ethnic people</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-mw-podcast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-mw-podcast/</guid><description>Dr Mark Wong | May 2022
Dr Mark Wong was interviewed for a podcast series, Spotlight, hosted by the University of Glasgow. I discussed the harms and bias in AI and data on Minoritised Ethnic people, with podcast host, Prof. Graeme Roy (Dean of External Engagement, College of Social Science, University of Glasgow). In the podcast, I also added new understanding to the importance of how we collect ethnicity data and information to inform public policy - and how the methods we use to collect and process information can themselves lead to biases in decision-making.</description></item><item><title>Talk at REPHRAIN Policy Salon</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-mw-rephrain-policy-salon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-mw-rephrain-policy-salon/</guid><description>Dr Mark Wong and Dr Aunam Quyoum
15 civil servants and representatives of government/public sector organisation attended a talk given by me (Mark Wong) and our project Research Associate, Aunam Quyoum, both at University of Glasgow, about the project. The talk was part of a series of REPHRAIN&amp;rsquo;s monthly hour-long “Policy Salons” held online, as part of a new initiative aimed at encouraging knowledge exchange and open discussions between policy makers, law enforcement agencies and REPHRAIN, the national centre of excellence on cybersecurity based at University of Bristol.</description></item><item><title>Invited Talk at Ofcom Internal Seminar Series</title><link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-mw-aq-ofcom-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/2022-mw-aq-ofcom-seminar/</guid><description>Dr Mark Wong and Dr Aunam Quyoum
140 Ofcom civil servants and policymakers attended a talk given by Dr. Mark Wong and Research Associate, Dr. Aunam Quyoum, both at University of Glasgow and part of the PRIME project. The talk was part of the Ofcom internal/academic seminar series. Their presentation introduced how our multi-institutional PRIME project examines online harms and bias of AI and data systems on Minoritised Ethnic people in digital health, housing, and energy services in the UK.</description></item></channel></rss>