<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Team on PRIME</title>
    <link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Team on PRIME</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 19:29:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.primecommunities.online/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Next Steps Prime Survey</title>
      <link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/next-steps-prime-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/next-steps-prime-survey/</guid>
      <description>A survey has been designed, piloted and translated into several community languages and is ready for launch later in March 2023. The survey is expected to hear from 1000 people who identify as a minoritised ethnic individual living in England and Scotland. We are working closely with our community partners to administer the survey and ensure our sample is reflective of the diversity of minoritised ethnic communities living in the UK.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRIME PANEL at the Scottish AI Summit April 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/prime-panel-scotttish-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/prime-panel-scotttish-summit/</guid>
      <description>In April 2023, PRIME PI Professor Gina Netto (Heriot Watt University (HWU)) chaired a panel which combined inputs from research team members Dr. Aunam Quyoum (University of Glasgow), Professor Lynne Baillie (HWU) and community organisation partners Colin Lee (Chief Executive, CEMVO Scotland) and Charles Kwaku-Odoi (Chief Officer, Caribbean &amp;amp; African Health Network (CAHN)) at the Scottish AI Summit. The Summit, held in Glasgow at the University of Strathclyde, brought together key notes and inputs from experts in Scotland’s AI community to facilitate conversations with diverse stakeholders.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRIME Participates in ‘End Digital Poverty Day’ 2023 </title>
      <link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/prime-participates-edpd-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/prime-participates-edpd-2023/</guid>
      <description>End Digital Poverty Day, a nationwide initiative dedicated to raising awareness about the pressing issue of digital poverty in the UK, takes place annually on 12 September. This year, the PRIME team participated in End Digital Poverty Day by publishing some of the project’s key findings in a blog post for the Digital Poverty Alliance.&#xA;The post centres the experiences of minority ethnic communities of digital poverty, drawing on 100 in depth interviews.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRIME Presents at the Digital Inclusion Policy and Research Conference 2023</title>
      <link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/prime-presents-digital-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 19:29:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/prime-presents-digital-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>In September 2023, PRIME project team members Dr Sara Bailey, Professor Agnes Kukulska-Hulme and Dr Elizabeth FitzGerald presented some of the PRIME project’s key findings at the University of Liverpool-hosted Digital Inclusion Policy and Research Conference (DIPRC 2023). The presentation took a deep dive into the experiences of older Asian and Asian British-identifying adults of using digital healthcare, housing and energy services. According to the Office for National Statistics (ONS), Asian and Asian-British individuals over the age of 55 are significantly less likely to use the internet than White individuals in the same age category.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prime Interviews Completed</title>
      <link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/prime-interviews-completed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 19:26:12 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/prime-interviews-completed/</guid>
      <description>The PRIME team has gained detailed insight into the various challenges minioritised ethnic citizens are facing when trying to access digital health, energy and housing services. The task to conduct 100 interviews with individuals across England and Scotland, was made possible by working in collaboration with our community organisation partners. In particular, our community partners supported us to recruit many minoritised ethnic individuals who do not currently use digital services effectively or who may have been reluctant to participate in an academic research project otherwise.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PRIME Multi-disciplinary Presentations at REPHRAIN’s ‘All Hands Meeting’ in Edinburgh</title>
      <link>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/prime-md-presentation-rephrain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 19:17:19 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.primecommunities.online/news/prime-md-presentation-rephrain/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Sara Bailey | 18 July 2024&#xA;Now that the hard work of data collection and data analysis is drawing to a close, the project team was delighted to have the opportunity to bring together researchers from both the social and computer sciences to provide a cross-disciplinary overview of our key findings to partners and stakeholders at the May 2024 ‘All Hands Meeting’ which was convened by REPHRAIN.&#xA;Of course, with 10 months remaining on the project, a good deal of work still remains to be done, especially for the team members involved in developing privacy-enhancing technologies and explainable AI that will help mitigate the online harms faced by minoritised ethnic (ME) communities when accessing online services, but this was a valuable opportunity to reflect on the progress made across the project so far.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
